and by December 22, the Sun's demise was fully realized
for the Sun, having moved south continually for six months
makes it to its lowest point in the sky.
Here a curious thing occurs.
The Sun stops moving south, at least perceivably, for three days.
And during this three-day pause, the Sun resides in the vicinity
of the Southern Cross constellation.
And after this time, on December 25, the Sun moves one degree,
this time north, foreshadowing longer days, warmth, and spring.
And thus it was said, the Sun died on the cross,
was dead for three days, only to be resurrected or born again.
This is why Jesus and numerous other sun gods share
the crucifixion, three-day death and resurrection concept.